okay hi I'm sorry I'm a little late I
thought today we'll do the Lions dance
of five rounds with me talking so if you
want to record it to use it in the next
you know you can use it for four five
days and then you don't need me okay
but then every month or something you
can check to see if you're still doing
it right or you added something
now that's good that's good
it's very good I'm happy
somebody's other people turn your phone
off
you getting wet so I should I should
talk slower
hi
duh Chung ah it's uh it's the ring it
never rains in Arizona so we don't know
what to do everything everything breaks
so blow your nose slowly first left side
and the right side then the middle
good okay
so we're gonna do the all five rounds of
the line stance I'm gonna try to do it
on a Saturday schedule so Saturday's not
as long as Sunday but uh you know I did
19 years in the corporation corporate
life me and John right you did 25 21
similar so Saturday morning
I used to sleep top they loved it I
don't know then you do your a good
meditation Sunday mornings the best long
and then Sunday around 2 o'clock you
start washing your clothes for Monday
that's corporate life ok here we go so
make sure you blow your nose make sure
your phone's turned on we asked a few
people to make noise during the first
round so don't forget you guys to move
around or crinkle some papers move your
chair Kelly you're just kidding ok here
we go so in normally we would watch our
breath to shift gears out of our normal
life into our meditation in the lion
stance its traditional to just jump
right in to following some sounds in the
room could be air conditioner
refrigerators are very useful if you
don't have children you might want to
have children so you can do good lions
dance and then have some noise in the
house so ten breaths is week day 20
breaths is a Sunday what we're doing
Saturday so let's say 12 to 15 breaths
each level so I'll I'll watch that you
don't have to worry about it unless
we're in the desire realm and we're
connecting to outside Sun and you're
resting your mind on that sound as if
you were resting your head on a pillow
so stay relaxed don't get tired every
time you feel a little rushed or a
little tight then do this trick of long
exhale and when you reach the end of the
exhale and the lungs naturally pause
then push a little more air out and that
will relax your body relax your mind so
anytime you personally feel tight tight
chest or your forehead feels tight then
take a exhale break to be report breath
long long exhale and then when the
abdomen naturally tightens then try to
exhale out just the last piece of breath
and we'll release extra prana and the
construction will go away okay here we
go
sounds in the room
then first forum level just called
number one and focus on your heart
beating in your chest try to withdraw
from the outside sounds and it won't be
perfect you can't do it 100% if someone
that makes a loud sound your mind will
go back to the outside world to the
desire around but then just gently come
back to the heartbeat don't make a big
deal about it just slowly come back to
the heartbeat you're still on your body
your big body
and rest your mind on the heartbeat in a
relaxed way as if your head was on a
pillow
then decide you'd like to go to a
quieter place gotcha you want to cancel
the noisier place which is being in your
whole party so you moved to a quieter
place each time we go up a level it
should feel like you're moving to a
quieter place and you are gently
rejecting the noisier place so let's go
to the quieter place inside the heart
and put your mind inside the heart I'm
sitting inside the heart and walls of
the heart around me are beating but it's
not dark or wet
it's a beautiful met a small meditation
room I like to put lots of cushions and
very comfortable the air is very sweet
and pure sunlight lots of sunlight
coming through their windows into heart
on the walls of the heart and it feels
pretty nice in here and it's quite
header we don't have a meditation object
yet we're just stretching out our
muscles mental muscles to get ready for
manatee
it would be quieter if I could go to
some separate space in the center of the
inside of the heart if the heart was
like a penthouse in a beautiful building
with lots of windows and there were lots
of rooms on the outs around the outside
and then there was a like a special room
on the inside not touching the outside
wall the center of the penthouse so the
outside walls have lots of windows and
lots of sunlight coming in but then I go
into a separate room on the inside you
can say the center of the heart and I
walk in there and I close the door and
it's even more quiet then inside the
heart it's the inside of the inside of
the heart still lots of sunlight perfect
temperature very comfortable and super
quiet
still no a meditation object just
getting the mind quieter if a sound
pulls you back to the desire realm then
just say hi I'm busy right now come back
to the center room inside the heart
super quiet
there's a small table next to you and on
the table there's a small pot of sugar
you take the lid off with your left hand
third finger you reach in and just touch
the top of the sugar lightly and when
you look at your finger
there's a few crystals of sugar choose
one and make a decision that in order to
go to a quieter place you would like to
sit in your mind hold mine into this
tiny crystal sugar so you kind of open
up one of the faces of the crystal like
a little door and you squeeze your mind
inside but when you get inside it's kind
of cool there's a whole big meditation
room very uncomfortable very spacious
like a like a nice spacious apartment
lots of light lots of sunlight and it
feels quite comfortable beautiful space
to meditate you can add you know flowers
or beautiful things and much quieter
inside this crystal so at the same time
that you're aware of a large beautiful
meditation space there's also this
feeling of focus like the tip of a
needle
or like a laser a pointer which is the
sugar crystalline so inside the heart
inside the inside of the heart stay here
in this single pointed spacious sunlit
space
now expand your mind purposely formless
realm number one the name is endless
space but we're going to expand the mind
inside it crystal the Pacific Ocean
stretching from pole to pole from shore
to shore endlessly if you drop a drop of
water in the middle then ripples would
travel slowly forever if you like you
can follow one of those ripples or
follow them in opposite directions and
inside this miracle inside the crystal
your mind is expanding like a huge ocean
and enjoy the feeling of spaciousness
infinity your mind as big as the Pacific
Ocean palm beautiful deep no real
meditation object here just stretching
our mental legs
now think about the mind that's
expanding watching the owner expand this
awareness
I'd like to imagine the sky
the light blue sky try to stretch my
mind along the limits of the sky
limitlessly if you like you can go
further stretch the mind itself the
observer beyond this guy into the space
outer space and there are countless
worlds there are countless beings there
are surely Buddha's have come to other
planets and there are surely people
doing lions dance at this moment in
other worlds maybe worlds that overlap
with our world so I'd like to imagine my
mind like a big bubble and as it expands
then sometimes it bumps into other
bubbles other people's minds and other
worlds doing the Lions dens right now
and I kind of like to say hi how's your
lions dance going so expander mine
certainly there are actually infinite
people doing the Lions dance right now
and let these minds together expand
but thinking itself is kind of noisy
let's go to a quieter place imagine your
mind to stop thinking altogether like
someone turned off a light
and thoughts have stopped if you see a
thought moving through the mind then
intercepted engage it and intercepted
like a missile and stop him and then
come back to the mind not thinking sir
formless realm never to me
forth formulas film though still the
mind is not thinking but if a thought
comes through the mind and just moved to
the center of the mind to the quiet
place in the center of the mind and let
those thoughts move to the mind like
clouds
they will dissolve they will call
someplace and I'm in the quiet place in
the center of the mind which is not
thinking this is not meditation this is
not a goal this is not a good place to
stop but we are just exercising our mine
before we start the real meditation
now we'll start the meditation now we're
warmed up it's similar to one of our
yoga teachers diametre he he makes you
do yoga for half an hour pretty hard and
then he says now we're warmed up now
let's start yoga so think about the
teachers in your life starting with your
father and your mother
maybe brothers or sisters people in your
family that you grew up with or
schoolteachers or other family members
who taught you valuable things and there
were particularly nice people good
example we all have a few special
teachers in earth early school or even
university sometimes a sports teacher or
singing teacher
art teacher
then there's the people who taught you
your job few special people who took
their time to teach you something that
helped you make your income
then there are spiritual teachers
priests rabbis Imam Lama someone you met
a special person in your life who
introduced you to spiritual things then
there are special teachers like pets or
children who taught you a lot there are
historical teachers there's your
historical teacher could be like Jesus
or Buddha Muhammad Confucius
lots
or
hard teachers it's nice to use your hard
teacher if you have a hard teacher some
of us would like to have a hard teacher
we didn't meet them yet but we have a
picture in our mind what we would like
to be a hard teacher so any of these
teachers bring one to the room ask them
to come in ask them to sit with you knee
to knee real person not a picture not a
movie not a video a real person in your
mind their body's warm they are
breathing some fragrance coming from
their body but the most important thing
is they're looking at you with great
love and great affection this is my
student this is my precious student
they're proud of you
meditating trying to help people
now choose something about your teacher
that you very much love some good
quality there's a reason why you love
the teacher there are pieces of them
that are especially beautiful to you and
choose one of the sweetest ones maybe
their patience maybe their compassion
maybe their knowledge maybe they're not
choose one of these qualities
focus on it
and don't forget it for the rest of the
meditation keeping in mind
then ask yourself why do I see this
quality where's this coming from
there's a feeling that this patience or
this compassion or this love was inside
of them when you met them
but imagine that this quality is coming
from seeds in your own mind it would be
fun to go find out where I was what I
was doing when I planted those seeds no
doubt because watermelon seeds make
watermelons it must have been similar I
must have had this kind of love or this
kind of patience in a past life so go
back to your past liar in your
imagination make a movie most of us
probably cannot see our past life
directing but we can imagine and what we
imagine is also coming from us so it's
partly true already so don't have doubt
anything that comes to your imagination
it's probably partly true so go back to
another country to another time it may
be completely different occupation may
be different sex maybe you were adopted
sex maybe you looked much different
different race of people
different language and try to make right
scenes of that person in the past life
what they were doing there created this
patience in my teacher make one scene
and don't be lazy if you have extra time
give it more detail
don't space out make it more and more
detailed exactly how did you help
someone what did they look like how did
you feel what was happening that evening
afterwards
all the details here we go have fun
don't worry about your legs
don't worry about your back give this
time to examination
and slowly gently come back to your
teacher kind of looking at them in a
different way you have more awareness of
why they have this beautiful quality it
doesn't make it less it makes it more it
makes it more real because now you know
where it's coming from you can keep it
going you it never has to get less it
can always get stronger and sweeter
all I have to do is have more patience
in my life more compassion for other
people I can always be surrounded by
people who teach me even my children
even my pets even people I meet in the
store they will show me in some
beautiful teaching I have the power to
create a world like this
because things are coming from my seas
my world can get sweeter and sweeter
there's one thing that can stop that
there's one force which can stop that
beautiful world and that's my own
mistaken thoughts to come up when you're
tired or hungry or lonely you are
confused then sometimes it's good to
bring those wrong thoughts to mind just
to see how they feel and learn to
recognize them and fight them so let's
do a wrong thinking exercise and get
used to what it looks like and then
there if it comes up in a week or a
moment of our day we can recognize it so
aster Lama - please move to the side and
bring up an imaginary teacher I like to
call it boo-boo Lama mistaken teacher
they look just the same they have the
same face same body same clothes they
have the same good quality
but my feeling about that quality is
that it comes from them it's inside them
when I met them and the first time I saw
this quality
I had a assumption in my mind I had a
belief unspoken believed that this
quality is coming from inside them it
lives inside them when they came to the
room when they walked in this room they
already had this quality inside them so
try to feel what it's like to have the
wrong idea about this teacher practice
what it feels like to think that this
quality is coming from inside them
because this is the kind of mistake
mistake in mine that causes our pain
this mind believes that the quality is
not coming from me and there's no way I
can keep it going or support it or
develop it myself it's inside of them
it's not coming from me so practice this
mistake in state of mind
so you can recognize it when it comes
and it comes up all day many times every
hour
though you can kind of make this fake
teacher disappear there's no such thing
it's an illusion
it never existed all the time I knew
there it never existed so make that fake
teacher disappear see that they are not
there they were never there and then try
to stay in this macaque tried to stay in
this absence of something which was
never there
this is emptiness and this is an
emptiness which is useful which can make
a perfect world
then slow they come out of that and
bring your teacher back the real one
love them have affection for them
admired their good quality they really
have it it's real it's more real enjoy
them for a moment
now you're tired it's been a long time
if you're meditating at home you might
want to open your eyes and take a break
now and then continue with the second
round of the meditation but since we've
been in retreat since tomorrow we have
to go home why don't we push ourselves
let's see if we can finish the whole
five rounds in one time take a few deep
exhales push the exhale out
try to remove any tightness and inside
you
if you're already tight and it feels
pretty strong then it's traditional to
move the meditation to the navel down
away from the heart which is a very
sensitive area and you can move it down
to the tight place where the exhale
tightens and move it a little to the
back
and continue the meditation their
comeback to the mind which is not
thinking the inner core of the mind some
thoughts are floating around on the
outside but in the inner core of the
mind it's quiet be tough when your body
hurts when you're tired that's the time
you make progress it's like shaking in a
yoga pose just hold it for one more
second we speed up the steps as we come
out maybe half the time you spend coming
in
back to the mine third-level now we have
thoughts in the mind but we are engaging
them blocking them little less quiet
than the center of the mind at the
fourth formless realm now which is
called to shame and shame amen
try to stay still it doesn't actually
help to move much you might as well just
stay still
come back to that expansive mind you can
use the sky you can imagine other people
meditating on other planets and your
mind is very very very huge infinite
consciousness
now let's go back to infinite space in
the ocean broad why as big as the world
maybe your ripples are coming back to
the center
they'll come back to the sugar crystal
in the middle of the ocean but now it's
the inner chamber of your heart
beautiful sunlight here very quiet
come back to the inner room up the
penthouse of your heart
a little bit less quiet you can hear the
heartbeat at a distance the outer walls
extra exhale
if you feel tight it also helps if you
feel tired or if some body some part of
your body is hurting push you out the
exhales focus on the exhale
come back to sitting inside the heart
beautiful sunlit open
and then come back to your body then
you're feeling your heart beam
let's show what a good retreat we had at
Diamond Mountain let's show how stronger
we are than when we started getting
Michael doesn't have to get me a break
and don't come out to the air
conditioner go back into the heart let's
go back up quickly show how fast you can
change your aspect up your mind now to
the center at the heart
now to the sugar crystal
a single point
now explode it as big as the ocean broad
broad broad still never stop keep
expanding now move into that state of
mind as big as the sky as big a space as
big as this universe
now let's stop thinking
my control of my mind is so strong I can
stop thinking
income today inside of the mind which is
stop thinking away from any thoughts
inside that space is your teacher happy
smiling loves you
and they have this beautiful quality
that's coming from me
let's jump down to the first level again
we're just finishing the meditation
we'll move quickly I'm inside my body
I'm watching my heart
No there's my llama again there's my
teacher again I love this quality about
them
now I'm inside my heart my teacher is
still there
that quality is coming from me
seeds are opening in my mind pictures
are coming up of patience or compassion
covering this person I'm in the inner
chamber of the heart o teacher is still
there
weren't this quality come from who made
it
is it natural I said part of them or is
it coming from somewhere else come to
the sugar crystal Oh teacher still there
and their quality came from me I was in
another country I was in another body I
look completely different but I had some
small seed for this patients I remember
doing things to help other people
let's expand the mine size of the ocean
maybe the ocean is filled with drops
that are filled with teachers maybe
every drop of the ocean as a teacher
inside
expanded the space itself still teachers
everywhere every star every planet
it's my teacher
let's start the mind
stop thought
in the center of that stuffed mind it's
a space and emptiness where my teacher
never was a teacher who had patients
inside of them when I met them in the
middle of the stock mine is a space
called emptiness where that teacher
never was
stop all that
let the real teacher come back
say hi or you're so cool and then let's
do the last round very quickly back to
the mine
we just stopped
let's show of how flexible we are even
when we're tired even when we're
exhausted let's go to the
air-conditioner
jump back to the mind with no thoughts
look how flexible my mind is go back to
space outer space go back to the sky
come back to the air-conditioner
go back to the oh yeah
sugar crystal
air conditioner
sinner tolerant
inside her air-conditioner
and then sit in your body and watch your
heart ask your llama to stay with you in
your heart wouldn't you like to sit in
my heart all day you're so sweet
sometimes I might need you when I don't
feel so much patience and I don't feel
very compassionate won't you help me
they say oh sure I'd like to be inside
your heart they start to rise up off
their Krisher
their body gets smaller and smaller
they come to the top of your head they
turn around same way facing the same way
and you can feel them land on the top of
your head soft warm like more money and
they shrink to the size of your
thumbnail and they start flowing down
your spine like more money you can feel
this little version of your Lama flowing
down your spine dear heart and you say
here it's a beautiful room for you I've
been meditating there today the question
still one lots of sunlight please stay
here help me when I need help today
inspire me or not need inspiration
three deep exhales give away the good
karma it's a great carmine share it with
the world it's like a fire offering
coming out of your lungs
it's like smoke from a fire offering
spreading to the whole world I give you
this paper I hope everyone can meditate
see these things then we'll have a
beautiful world
slowly open your eyes take a stretch
wow that was a while I think that's for
Sunday forget Saturday maybe it's for
your annual vacation I think we should
just take a break from there okay I
think we all need a break
if you have questions so when we get
back okay so take a nice break we have a
lot of things to do today unfortunately